powerlinks.com 2019-06-30

# PowerLinks Privacy Policy - PowerLinks

**POWERLINKS**

**PRIVACY POLICY**

PowerLinks is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy sets out the basis on which any information which you provide to us or which we collect from you will be processed by us. It also provides details of the technologies we use to collect information, including cookies.

Please read this document carefully before you start to use [www.powerlinks.com](http://www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net/). By continuing to access our site you are agreeing to this policy. If you do not agree, please refrain from using our site.

PowerLinks is an advertising and marketing software platform which enables Advertisers (or Buyers) and Publishers (or Sellers) and third parties acting on their behalf, to buy and sell advertising space. We also provide technologies (including those of third party suppliers) which enable Advertisers to deliver ads to the most relevant audiences, by using a number of techniques including interest based, real time, contextual and geographical advertising, and to measure how effective their ads are. We refer to all of these third parties as “Partners”.

Our site is operated by PowerLinks Media Limited. We are a company registered in England and Wales with company number 08012063. We also have offices in London and New York. You can find our contact details below.

**_Information which you provide to us_**

We may collect and process data about you which you voluntarily provide to us. This includes information provided by you at the time of registering your interest by completing a form on our website, registering to use our site or when you report a problem with our site. If you contact us, we may keep a record of the relevant communications.

**_Information which we collect_**

We collect information which is in our legitimate interests as an advertising and marketing  advertising platform to provide Services to our Partners.

We may use a variety of technologies which store or access information from your device (such as on your browser, operating system, hardware, identifiers, mobile network information). Your device is any device used to access our website such as a personal computer, laptop, tablet or mobile phone. We may obtain information about your device, system and general internet usage by using cookies and/or web beacon files or similar technologies which are stored on your device.

Examples of data that might be collected include information about your device, your IP address, operating system, Internet Service Provider (ISP), pages viewed and linked from, browsing and usage habits, search terms, domain name, geographical location, times and dates of visits and browser type, interactions with advertisements.

We also receive information from and share information with third parties to help us to analyse the information we have collected, to improve our Services and to enable Advertisers to serve you with an ad which may be of interest to you.

If you are accessing our site from within the European Union, some of this information may be classed as ‘Personal Data’ under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). You can learn more about your rights under the GDPR below: **EU Data Subject Rights.** Any personal information which we collect is ‘anonymised’ by attributing a unique digital identifier. We do not collect any data which identifies you as an individual (such as your name and address, email address or telephone number). We prohibit our Partners from sharing such information with us.

**_How We Collect Information_**

We use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies to help us to operate and improve our Services.

A few of the methods that may be used to store or access information already stored on your device include the following, (and in future other technologies may be developed and you are required to check this policy regularly for any changes):

**“Cookies** ” A cookie is a small text file of letters and/or numbers that we store on your device when you visit our website, provided that you consent. Cookies can be temporary (e.g. session cookies) or permanent (e.g. persistent cookies). They can also be first party (e.g. placed by us) or third party (e.g. placed by a third-party advertiser or advertisements server).

– **strictly necessary cookies** are required for the operation of our website

– **analytical/performance cookies** allow us to count the number of users and track your movement [on our website]

– **functionality cookies** are used to recognise returning users to personalise [our website service]

– **targeting cookies** record your visit [to our website] and information is used to display adverts that may be of interest to you, namely: anonymous identifiers, web beacons, embedded scripts, entity tags or ETags.

We also use cookies placed by a third party, primarily to monitor our server status and performance. Information on these cookies can be found at: [https://new-relic-cookies](https://docs.newrelic.com/docs/subscriptions/new-relic-cookies)

Please note that our Partners may use cookies and/or web beacons or similar technologies on your device through our site. They may, for example, use information about your visits to websites to serve ads to you which may be of interest. We contractually require our Partners to obtain your consent to do so. Our Partner’s use of these technologies is not subject to this PowerLinks Privacy Policy, but is subject to the policies of those Partners.

It is possible to set your computer to refuse to accept cookies (which will also stop operation of web beacons). Some cookies we use are essential for parts of our website to operate, so please be aware that if you disable or delete these technologies some parts of our website may not work. To learn more about cookies, including what cookies have been set, on your browser, visit: [www.allaboutcookies.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)org.

**_How we use the information we collect_**

We collect non-identifiable information for legitimate business interests, namely;

-To operate, maintain and provide our Services to our Partners as required by our Agreements with them,

-To ensure compliance by our Partners when using our Services,

-To serve relevant ads to target audiences,

-To report on ad performance and delivery,

-To measure the effectiveness of an ad,

-To analyse trends

– To detect and prevent fraudulent activity and prevent infringement of third party rights or any other misuse of our Services..

**_Disclosure of your information to our Partners_**

We share the information we collect with our Partners for the following purposes;

– To enable Advertisers to serve you with targeted ads which may be of interest to you,

– To enable Advertisers to measure and improve the effectiveness of an ad campaign,

– To enable Publishers to measure how Users are engaging with their sites and ads served on their sites,

– To our sub-contractors and suppliers for the purpose of providing services to us.

– To enable us to monitor our Partners’ use of our Services,

– To enable us to enforce our rights under the Agreements with our Partners for the use of our Services,

– To detect and prevent fraudulent activity and prevent infringement of third party rights or any other misuse of our Services.

– To comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply this Policy or our Terms and Conditions and other Agreements, or to protect our rights, property, or safety.

– We may disclose your information to any member of our group of companies, which means any of our subsidiaries.

– In the event that we are involved in a merger or the purchase or sale of all or substantially all of our business or assets, in which case we may disclose this information to the prospective buyer.

– In response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our Partners, but we may provide them with statistical or aggregated information for our legitimate business interests namely, the provision of our Services. For example, we may inform them that 900 women aged over 40 have clicked on their ad on any given day. We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. For example, we may assist them to deliver an ad to men in Manchester. Since there is no reasonable way to extract data which could identify you from this data, such disclosure does not affect your privacy.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of others. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**_Where we store the information we collect_**

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our Suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the provision of support services and helping us maintain our site and provide our Services.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely, in accordance with current legislation and regulations concerning the collection and storage of such information accepted industry standards and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access to any information we receive.

**_How long we store Information we collect_**

We anonymise and aggregate data at the point of collection. We may retain and use the information we collect for as long as necessary to provide our Services to our Partners. We may retain some types of information for reporting and analytical purposes and for improving our Services, to resolve disputes and enforce our Agreements with Partners and to comply with legal obligations and requirements. We may store and retain such information for up to six years. We will make efforts to ensure that information is kept for no longer than is necessary.

**_Industry Self-Regulation_**

We support, comply with and are registered as a vendor with the [IAB Europe Transparency and Consent Framework](http://advertisingconsent.eu/) (‘The Framework’) which provides consumers with full visibility and control over who is allowed to process their data in connection with advertising, and for what purposes. You can find out more about the Framework here http://advertisingconsent.eu/

**_Your Rights and Choices_**

**_Opting-out_**

To opt-out of receiving communications from us, (as a result of you having provided us with your contact information) by contacting us at [mailto:info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net](mailto:info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net)

If you do not want to receive ads displayed by PowerLinks, you can disable the display of PowerLinks ads here. Please note that This opt-out relies on a cookie, so if you wipe all your cookies, we will no longer know that you have opted out.

You have the right to opt-out from the use of information collection technologies. Regular cookies may be disabled or deleted, and in some instances, can be blocked in the future, by selecting certain settings on your browser and device. You should seek guidance from the official websites or manuals relating to the browser or device. You can find out how to manage cookies by visiting the following web browser websites:

The opt-out only applies to the browser you are using. So, if you use different browsers, you will need to opt-out on each browser. Please also note that opting-out does not block all cookies.

You can opt-out from the collection and use of your personal information for the purposes of receiving targeted advertisements. Further information concerning your rights and options in relation to information collection can be found on the Digital Advertising Alliance website at: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> and/or [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or for users in the European Economic Area, the EDAA at <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>

**_Your Rights_**

You can contact us at [info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net](mailto:info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net) and request to access any personal information which we may have about you. You can request us to delete any personal information which you have provided via our Site and we will respond in a reasonable time. Deletion of data will not change or delete personal information which may have already been shared with third parties. Please note that any data we collect is anonymized at the point of collection. We may therefore need to ask you to provide further information to make sure that you are who you claim to be and to assist us in responding to your request. Since we do not collect information about identifiable human beings, it is unlikely that we will be able to provide you with any information which identifies you.

**_EU Data Subject Rights under the GDPR_**

Under the General Data Protection Regulation Regulation (EU) 2016/679, some of the information which we collect (as described above), is classified as ‘Personal Data’.

As an EU resident, you have rights concerning the collection, processing and use of this information. You have the right to (i) access any of your personal data held by us (ii) ask us to rectify, amend, erase or transfer such personal data and (iii) restrict the processing of your personal data. You also have the right to object to the processing of your personal data for the purposes of direct marketing and the right not to be subject to automated decision making, including profiling. To find out more about your rights under the GDPR visit: [EU data-protection rules 2018](https://ec.europa.eu/commission/priorities/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/2018-reform-eu-data-protection-rules_en)

If you have any concerns about the way in which we collect or process your data, please contact us here:[info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net](http://info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net/)  or by writing to us at: PowerLinks Media Limited, 9th Floor, 80 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3FX. We will respond within 30 days. If you are not satisfied with our response you also have the right to complain to the data-protection regulator in the country where you live or work. For the UK, you should contact the Information Commissioner here: [https://ico.org.uk/.](https://ico.org.uk/)

**_EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks_**

PowerLinks complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks, as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield programme and to view our certificate, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, we are committed to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact us at: [info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net](http://info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net/) or by writing to us at: PowerLinks Media Limited, 9th Floor, 80 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3FX.

If PowerLinks does not resolve your complaint, you may submit your complaint, free of charge, to The International Centre for Dispute Resolution (ICDR) which is the international division of the American Arbitration Association  (ICDR/AAA). ICDR/AAA is PowerLinks chosen independent dispute resolution provider: You can find out more about ICDR/AAA and how to lodge a complaint here: <https://www.icdr.org./>Under certain conditions specified by the principles of the EU-US and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks, respectively, you may also be able to invoke binding arbitration to resolve your complaint.

PowerLinks is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

If PowerLinks shares the personal data of an individual located in the EU or Switzerland with a third-party service provider that processes the data solely on PowerLinks’ behalf, then PowerLinks will be liable for that third-party’s processing of that data in violation of the Principles, unless PowerLinks can prove that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

**_Contacting Us_**

You can contact us at [info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net](http://info@www-powerlinks.azurewebsites.net/) or by writing to us at PowerLinks Media Limited, 9th Floor, 80 Mosley Street, Manchester, M2 3FX. This address should also be used to send us any questions, comments and requests regarding this Policy, or if you have any concerns relating to material on our sites.

**_Changes to this Policy_**

We may revise this policy at any time by amending this page. You should check this page from time to time to take notice of any changes we make. Where necessary, we will seek your consent to these changes. We will always display clearly when the privacy policy was last amended on the website.

**Last updated 13 September   2018**
